Breaking Away mss., 1978-1982 LMC 2927
Lilly Library
Breaking Away mss.
1978-1982
Lilly Library
Schwoegler, Thomas
LMC 2927
1 Box
The Breaking Away mss., 1978-1982, consist of production materials, press kits, and ephemera related to the film Breaking Away and its international versions.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift: 2015
Biographical / Historical
Breaking Away (1979) is an Academy Award-winning film centering on four teenagers in Bloomington, Indiana, who form a cycling team for the Little 500, an annual bicycle race held at Indiana University.
Thomas Schwoegler is a long-time Little 500 coach who consulted for and acted in Breaking Away.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of promotional materials, correspondence, production materials, posters, press kits, and ephemera from the film Breaking Away collected by Thomas Schwoegler, consultant to the film and longtime Little 500 coach.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged following original order.
Bloomington (Ind.).; Motion picture film; Cycling; Breaking away (Motion picture)
- Audio-Visual Material
  - Jo Jeeta Wohi Sikandar DVD, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Breaking Away Poster Scans Disc, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- News and Magazine Clippings, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Invitations Correspondence and University Documents, 1978-1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Production Materials, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bill York's Blooming-Toons Metal Artpiece, 1973-04-03 (Box 1)
- Press Packets, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Breaking Away Pressbook, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Breaking Away Japanese Pressbook, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Star Magazine, 1979-04-08 (Box 1)
- Breaking Away Television Series ABC photograph, 1980 (Box 1)
- Indiana Unversity Foundation Breaking Away Folder, 1979 (Box 1)
- Twentieth Century FOX Internation Press Material folder, 1979 (Box 1)
- Breaking Away Press Kit, 1979 (Box 1)